<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian's Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.bsu.me/</link>
    <description>A place where I'll share my latest travel stories, academic thoughts, and personal musings.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Great Podcasts I Recommend</title>
      <link>http://blog.bsu.me//podcasts</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    This summer, I spend at least 40 minutes in my car and about 2 hours on a bus to work each workday. That's a lot of time to kill! What I can't stand are the songs they play on the radio - 94.9, 97.3, 99.7, 101.3, 101.7. They are repetitive and trashy,
    maybe except Taylor Swift, whom I usually enjoy listening to. As I spend more time on the road, I have realized that podcasts are the way to go for long commutes. Depending on your selection, they can be interesting, educational, and make you feel
    like you've learned something useful during the day. Here are some my recommendations, all available on iTunes and the Podcasts app, which I'll continually update over time as I discover more:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/&quot;&gt;Planet Money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I started listening to Planet Money in high school. The podcast focuses on local and global topics, such as
            &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/05/27/479717380/episode-703-how-to-hide-a-million-dollars-in-plain-sight&quot;&gt;
     like hiding a million dollars in plain sight&lt;/a&gt;,
            &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/03/02/468953007/episode-687-buy-this-passport&quot;&gt;countries selling citizenship&lt;/a&gt;, and
            &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/04/20/475023002/episode-468-kid-rock-vs-the-scalpers&quot;&gt;ticket scalping&lt;/a&gt;. They even &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/03/16/470722656/episode-390-we-set-up-an-offshore-company-in-a-tax-haven&quot;&gt;
              setup an offshore company&lt;/a&gt; to understand how it works. Each episode is an investigation into the topic, with a several interviews with experts and ordinary people and is well narrated. I've learned a lot from just listening to these podcasts.
            Here are some of my recommendations:
            &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/03/11/470136949/episode-689-a-hedge-fund-a-country-and-a-big-sailboat&quot;&gt;
                    What happens when a country, Argentina, refuses to pay its debts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/03/09/469674457/episode-418-how-the-government-set-up-a-fake-bank-to-launder-drug-money&quot;&gt;
                      How the government setup a fake bank to launder drug money and uncover the drug cartel?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2016/01/29/464859624/episode-680-anatomy-of-a-scam&quot;&gt;
                  How does a scam work and who gets scammed?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/money/2015/12/23/460689797/episode-671-an-insider-trader-tells-all&quot;&gt;
                  Getting caught insider trading.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/show/startup/&quot;&gt;Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Ever wanted to know what is it really like to have a startup? Well, you can finally do so, without the spending the long hours and many $$ needed to actually start one. In &lt;i&gt;Startup&lt;/i&gt;, the hosts follow startups through several important
            stages in their lives. Each episode involves recorded conversations between founders, partners, and even family members, who often feel a big impact when one of them is running a startup. In the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/1-how-not-to-pitch-a-billionaire/&quot;&gt;first season&lt;/a&gt;,
            the show follows
            &lt;i&gt;Gimlet Media&lt;/i&gt;, the company behind this show, and shows the process of starting a startup, including getting investors, communicating with the spouse, and finding a name for the startup. The &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/origin-story-season-2-1-2-3-4/&quot;&gt;second season&lt;/a&gt;            follows a online dating site
            &lt;i&gt;Dating Ring&lt;/i&gt; and how the startup life is like for female founders. In the current season, the show tells the stories of several startups, including &lt;i&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/almost-famous-season-3-episode-1/&quot;&gt;Justin.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;,
            the predecessor to &lt;i&gt;Twitch&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/pirate-needs-pirate-season-3-episode-3/&quot;&gt;Pirate Joe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a company that smuggles Trader Joe goods across to the Canadian border, and a food delivery
            company called &lt;i&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/kitchen-confidential-season-3-episode-6/&quot;&gt;Bento&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, which is undergoing a possible shutdown. It's a fascinating insight into the world of startups, and I would
            highly recommend it if you ever wanted to know about startups or wanted to start one yourself.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/show/reply-all/&quot;&gt;Reply All&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;i&gt;Reply All&lt;/i&gt; is another &lt;i&gt;Gimlet Media&lt;/i&gt; podcast and focuses on internet related topics, such as conspiracies, online dating, and more. I don't listen to this podcast that often, but there is one story that stands outs out called &lt;i&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/28-shipped-to-timbuktu/&quot;&gt;Shipped to Timbuktu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.
            I don't want to spoil anything, but this is a must listen! I also found the following quite interesting:
            &lt;ul&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/27-the-fever/&quot;&gt;The perils of online dating as an asian woman.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/25-favor-atender/&quot;&gt;In Ecuador, you can talk directly to the President on social media. But doing so could be dangerous.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;
                    &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/episode/ive-killed-people-and-i-have-hostages/&quot;&gt;The SWAT team vs. the internet.&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.thetalkingmachines.com&quot;&gt;Talking Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This is a new podcast that I recently discovered and focuses on the theory and applications of machine learning. It appears to be both academic and practical and I'd love to check this out more.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://partiallyderivative.com&quot;&gt;Partially Derivative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I've also discovered this one recently. This one focuses on the world of data science.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://serialpodcast.org&quot;&gt;Serial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I'm looking forward to listening to this podcast. Each season tells a captivating story from the beginning to the end. I'll let you guys know what I think soon! Here's season one's introduction:
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;A high-school senior named Hae Min Lee disappeared one day after school in 1999, in Baltimore County, Maryland. A month later, her body was found in a city park. And two weeks after that, her former boyfriend and classmate, 17-year-old
                    Adnan Syed, was arrested for the crime. He was convicted, and sentenced to life in prison. Syed has always said he had nothing to do with Lee’s death. Sarah Koenig sorted through thousands of documents, listened to trial testimony
                    and police interrogations, and talked to everyone she could find about what happened between Adnan Syed and Hae Min Lee. What she discovered is a story far more complicated than the jury, or the public, ever got to hear.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            And here's season two's introduction:
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;
                    In May 2014, a U.S. Special Operations team in a Black Hawk helicopter landed in the hills of Afghanistan. Waiting for them were more than a dozen Taliban fighters and a tall American, who looked pale and out of sorts: Bowe Bergdahl. Bergdahl, a U.S.
                    soldier, had been a prisoner of the Taliban for nearly five years, and now he was going home.
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;
                    President Obama announced Bergdahl’s return in the Rose Garden, with the soldier's parents at his side. Bergdahl's hometown of Hailey, Idaho, planned a big celebration to welcome him back. But then, within days—within hours of his rescue, in fact—public
                    reaction to his return flipped. People started saying Bergdahl shouldn’t be celebrated. Some of the soldiers from his unit called him a deserter, a traitor. They said he had deliberately walked off their small outpost in eastern Afghanistan
                    and into hostile territory.
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;
                    Hailey canceled its celebration. The army launched an investigation. Finally, in March, the military charged Bergdahl with two crimes, one of which carries the possibility of a life sentence. Through all of this, Bergdahl has been quiet. He hasn’t spoken
                    to the press or done any interviews on TV. He’s been like a ghost at the center of a raucous fight.
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;
                    Now, in Season Two, we get to hear what he has to say.
                &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Enigma Machine</title>
      <link>http://blog.bsu.me//enigma</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During World War II, the Enigma machine was widely used by the German forces
to communicate sensitive information amongst themselves. Believed by the Germans to be
unbreakable, the Enigma had a series of rotors and a single reflector at the
end. The first rotor would map the initial input into an output letter, which
is then passed to the subsequent rotors in similar fashion. Upon reaching the
reflector, which also maps its input to an output, the translation happens in
reverse, where the output of the reflector is passed through the last rotor all
the way to the first rotor, where it is then given back as an encoded letter.
To decode, the encoded message would be passed through the Enigma machine with
the same initial state, and the original message would show up.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <dc:date>2016-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </channel>
</rss>