<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>blog.bsu.me/</title>
   
   <link>http://blog.bsu.me/</link>
   <description>A place where I'll share my latest travel stories, academic thoughts, and personal musings.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Brian Su</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Asia Winter 2016. The Beginning.</title>
	  <link>//asia1</link>
	  <author>Brian Su</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//asia1</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>
    Last winter, in the span of 27 days, I traveled to Asia and visited 6 different countries,
    rode on 12 different flights, ate tons of delicious food, and made many new friends.
    Here I am, many days after the trip, reflecting upon my trip. Here’s my best
    recollection of everything that happened each day.
</p>
<p>
    I left San Jose International Airport near noontime onboard All Nippon Airways Flight
    171, operated by a Boeing 787–800. Nothing noteworthy happened on this flight;
    I got a middle seat on the right section of the aircraft. Fast-forward 10 hours
    later, I’m in Narita!
</p>
<p>
    After exchanging money at the airport, I headed downstairs towards the airport express
    train station. As I soon learned, Japanese people are extremely friendly towards
    others. I approached the station counter to buy a ticket towards Nippori station
    and after coughing over 2400¥ for my ticket, I headed downstairs to the platform.
    The train departed 10 minutes after I arrived and 36 minutes later, I was at
    Nippori station.
</p>
<p>
    Before I had left Narita airport, I took screenshots of the path to my hotel, Hotel
    Lungwood. So, after a little difficulty placing myself on the map, I was able
    to head in the right direction. I overshot where I had to go by a block, which
    happened for several more times before I finally figured it out, I arrived at
    my hotel and checked in at around 5pm.
</p>
<p>
    At around 6:30pm, I decided to leave my hotel and headed towards Shinjuku. I wanted
    to catch a glimpse of Tokyo at night at the Tokyo Metropolitan Government Building
    (free) and then also buy a data sim card at Yodabashi Camera, which my hotel
    front desk recommended to go to.
</p>
<p>
    Walking to the Metropolitan from the subway station took about 10 minutes and after
    a quick elevator ride up to the 45th floor, I was able to indulge in the breathtaking
    views of Tokyo!
</p>
<p>
    Upon leaving the Tokyo Metropolitan, I headed towards the shops near Shinjuku station.
    Initially, I found a store that had Yodobashi written in Kanji (after character
    matching, which I had to do again in Korea), but, walking inside, I saw nothing
    more than lots of console games, anime, Nitendo, etc. A store clerk, who spoke
    very little English, directed me to another store in the same district for my
    sim cards and I bought my sim cards there for about 1900¥.
</p>
<p>
    By this time, I was getting pretty hungry. Yet, at the same time, I was quite nervous
    on walking in to a restaurant and figuring out how to order. After all, what’s
    there to be afraid of?
</p>
<p>
    After walking up and down the streets looking for my first Japanese restaurant to
    dine at, I settled on a cute little ramen shop. The waiters/chef greeted me as
    a I walked and pointed towards the ticketing machine. They realized I was clueless
    as to how to use it and one of them helped me order my first ramen from the machine.
    I just picked the one that had the nicest picture.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, the ramen wasn’t dispensed from the machine. My friends thought I had
    bought instant ramen on my first day in Japan. After ordering and paying at the
    machine, the waiter takes the order and the chef makes it. I guess it saves the
    restaurant workers from ever touching dirty money, which I suspect isn’t really
    that dirty in Japan. After all, Japan was so clean!
</p>
<p>
    The ramen cost about 900¥ and it was absolutely delicious! My stomach grumbles at
    the sight of the picture above. The noodles, the soup, the pork loin — they were
    all on point. My only gripe? They didn’t give enough, especially the meat, which
    I realized was a trend all over Japan. Granted, I was judging Japanese cuisine
    under my American culturally indoctrinated platter portion expectations. Anyways,
    following my delicious meal, I took the metro back to my hotel and got some good
    rest.
</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
